<?xml version="1.0"?>
<metadata xml:lang="en"><Esri><CreaDate>20180725</CreaDate><CreaTime>09250300</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><ArcGISstyle>North American Profile of ISO19115 2003</ArcGISstyle><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce><ModDate>20180813</ModDate><ModTime>155800</ModTime><scaleRange><minScale>150000000</minScale><maxScale>5000</maxScale></scaleRange></Esri><toolbox name="EDAC" alias="ArcGIS Building Toolbox"><arcToolboxHelpPath>c:\program files (x86)\arcgis\desktop10.5\Help\gp</arcToolboxHelpPath><toolsets/></toolbox><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle>EDAC</resTitle></idCitation><idPurp>This toolbox extracts building footprints using LiDAR LAS 1.4 tiles.</idPurp><idAbs>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This toolbox extracts building footprints using LiDAR LAS 1.4 tiles.  The tool requires both the LAS and bare earth DEM tiles (as an Imagine .img, TIFF or ESRI Grid format) to be in separate folders and sharing the same naming convention.  The Building Object Extractor tool takes these files and a user defined minimum height above ground for a building to create output building raster objects.  These objects are then filtered using only the rooftop height standard deviation using the SD Building Filter or also the average rooftop NDVI value (for those with an equivalent resolution derived NDVI) by using the NDVI Building Filter.  The results from these filters are then converted to vector polygons, filtered based on a minimum roof area and the edges cleaned up to create the building footprint polygons.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</idAbs><idCredit>This toolbox was created by the Earth Data Analysis Center at the University of New Mexico as part of a contract from the Federal Emergency Management Agency - Region 6.</idCredit><searchKeys><keyword>LiDAR</keyword><keyword>LAS 1.4</keyword><keyword>building footprints</keyword><keyword>DEM</keyword><keyword>NDVI</keyword></searchKeys></dataIdInfo><distInfo><distributor><distorFormat><formatName>ArcToolbox Toolbox</formatName></distorFormat></distributor></distInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"/></mdHrLv><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20180810</mdDateSt></metadata>
